Ricardo Piglia Papers, 1954-2016: Finding Aid C1513
Manuscripts Division
Ricardo Piglia Papers
1954-2016
Manuscripts Division
Princeton University. Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections
Piglia, Ricardo
C1513
73 boxes
Ricardo Piglia was an Argentine author and professor emeritus of the Department of Spanish and Portuguese Languages and Cultures at Princeton University. His papers contain handwritten and typewritten drafts of his writings, diaries and journals, notebooks, loose handwritten research notes, teaching files, correspondence, personal photographs, and born-digital materials.
Scope and Contents
The papers include Ricardo Piglia's journals, research notebooks, and address books, most of which are handwritten. The papers also contain handwritten, typewritten, print out drafts, and published versions of Piglia's articles, novels, essays, opera, and film scripts. A large portion of the papers include loose page research notes and drafts. Other materials present in the papers include contracts and legal files; correspondence; academic career and teaching files; personal and professional photographs; printed materials featuring interviews or reviews about Piglia's work; and a collection of others work on Piglia.
Also included are born-digital materials, including files extracted from floppy disks and optical media, including DVDs and CDs. The floppy disks consist of about 70 digital files, dating from January 1999 to July 2003. The optical media consist of about 85314 digital files, dating from 1990 to 2015, and primarily consist of DVDs containing Piglia's various computer backups. The majority of the materials consist of files containing various drafts by Piglia; notes; corrections; correspondence; academic and teaching files, including numerous files from Piglia's tenure at Princeton University; documents related to conferences, presentations, trips; and others.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection contains digital files in the following formats: Microsoft Word, PDF, Rich Text, WordPerfect, Microsoft PowerPoint, Plain Text, XML, JPEG, and others. Refer to our Tips on Accessing Born-Digital Content for information on how to render these file formats.
Access to digital material in this collection is available on-site in the Special Collections Firestone Reading Room. Requests to access digital material from this collection must be placed at least 3 days in advance. For more information please contact Special Collections Public Services staff.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Guillermo Schavelzon (Ricardo Piglia's literary agent) in 2015 (AM 2016-35; AM 2017.144). This collection was purchased in part with funds provided by the Program in Latin American Studies (PLAS).
Appraisal
Non-archival printed materials and administrative files relating to personnel matters were removed from the 2018 processing.
Biographical / Historical
Ricardo Emilio Piglia Renzi was an Argentine author, critic, and screenwriter. He was professor emeritus of the Department of Spanish and Portuguese Languages and Cultures and the Walter S. Carpenter Professor of Language, Literature and Civilization of Spain at Princeton University. He was born on November 24, 1941, in Adrogué, a province of Buenos Aires, Argentina. In 1955, his family moved to Mar del Plata where he studied history at the Universidad Nacional de La Plata. He left for Buenos Aires to begin work in literary editorials in 1965. In 1967 he published his first book La invasión, which later received the Casa de las Américas prize. In 1975 he published his first volume of essays Nombre falso which includes an homage to Roberto Arlt (Homenaje a Roberto Arlt). Piglia's literary criticism centers around the themes of the Argentine novel, genre, fiction, translation, Argentine political history, and the works of various writers such as Roberto Arlt, Jorge Luis Borges, Macedonio Fernández, Leopoldo Lugones, Domingo Faustino Sarmiento, and Horacio Quiroga. Piglia's essays and novels — which include Respiración artificial (1980) and Blanco nocturno (2010) — have been translated into English, French, Italian, German and Portuguese. Several of his novels, including Plata quemada (1997) were adapted as films. His novel La ciudad ausente (1992) was adapted as an opera and premiered in the Teatro Colón in 1995. He also wrote several screenplays including Foolish Heart (1998), Plata quemada (2000), and El astillero (1999). Piglia kept a journal for most of his life and published various autobiographical volumes under the name of his alter ego, Emilio Renzi: Los años de formación (1957-1967) in 2015; Los años felices (1968-1975), in 2016; and Un día en la vida, in 2017. He taught at the Universidad de Buenos Aires from 1990 to 2000. Prior to joining Princeton's faculty he taught at the University of California at San Diego, University of California at Davis, and Harvard University. He first arrived to Princeton as a visiting fellow in the Humanities Council in 1986-1987; and was a frequent visiting professor prior to joining the Princeton University faculty in 2001. During his teaching career at Princeton he taught courses on Argentine literature, the detective genre, Jorge Luis Borges, Macedonio Fernández, Juan José Saer, and Rodolfo Walsh. He retired from Princeton in 2011. Piglia received numerous awards, including the Premio Casa de las Américas (1967), a Guggenheim Fellowship (1989), Premio Planeta (1997), Premio internacional de novela Rómulo Gallegos (2011), and Premio Iberoamericano de las Letras (2005), the Premio Iberoamericano de Letras José Donoso (2005). In 2014 he won the Diamond Konex Award. He died in Buenos Aires on January 6, 2017 at the age of 75.
Authors, Argentine; Authors, Latin American -- 20th century -- Interviews.; Latin American literature -- 20th century.; Audiocassettes -- 20th century.; Correspondence -- 20th century.; Interviews -- 20th century.; Photographs -- 20th century.; Born digital.; Borges, Jorge Luís, 1899-1986; Piglia, Ricardo
- Series 1: Journals and Notebooks, 1953-2014; 19 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  Arrangement
  This series is organized by subseries, then chronologically with undated items arranged first.
  Scope and Contents
  Includes handwritten journals, notebooks, and yearly agendas. Folder titles are derived from the following sources when available: cover titles, first entry date, and notebook brand in parenthesis. Many include inset ephermal materials such as receipts, letters, maps, and boarding passes.
  - Subseries 1: Journals, 1954-2014; 8 boxes
    Chronologically with undated items arranged first.
    Includes bound and loose page personal journals Piglia kept throughout most of his life. Folder titles are derived from the following sources when available: cover titles, first entry date, and notebook brand in parenthesis.
    - Ricardo E. Piglia (a) El loco - (Avon Journal), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 1)
    - Diario (Loose Pages), 1954-1955; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 2)
    - Domingo, 14 de septiembre (Cuaderno Extra Journal), 1958; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 3)
    - Domingo, 14 de septiembre (Tomo I - Black Journal), 1958; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 4)
    - Lunes, 22 de junio (Journal), 1959; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 5)
    - Sábado, 26 de septiembre (La materia en el arte Journal), 1959; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 6)
    - Martes, 6 de octubre (Tomo II - Black Journal), 1959-1969; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 7)
    - Lunes, 28 de diciembre (Cuaderno Extra Journal), 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 8)
    - Enero - 19 de mayo (Tomo III - Black Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 9)
    - 7 de enero (Loose Pages) y 1 de junio (Mascota Rayado Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 10)
    - Lunes, 15 de febrero (No Cover Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 11)
    - Mayo 27 (Loose Typewritten Pages), 1960-1961; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 12)
    - Viernes, 22 de julio (Mar del Plata, La materia en el arte Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 13)
    - Domingo, 24 de julio (Black Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 14)
    - Lunes, 24 de octubre (La Plata, No Cover Journal), 1960; 1 folder (Box B-001108, Folder 15)
    - Sábado, 21 de mayo (Tomo I - Black Journal); 5 de abril (Black Journal); Libros franceses (Black Journal), 1960-1969; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 1)
    - 6 de enero (Mar del Plata - La materia en el Arte 40 hojas Journal), 1961; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 2)
    - Miércoles, 26 de julio (Cuba - Triunfo Cuaderno escolar 48 hojas Journal), 1961; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 3)
    - Miércoles, 27 de septiembre (Triunfo 100 hojas Notebook), 1961; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 4)
    - Viernes, 8 de diciembre (Triunfo 100 hojas Journal), 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 5)
    - 2 agosto (Black Journal), 1963-1971; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 6)
    - Enero (Black Journal); Enero (Black Journal), 1964-1971; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 7)
    - 1 de julio (Black Journal), circa 1964-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001109, Folder 8)
    - Jueves, 3 de diciembre (Black Journal), circa 1964-1968; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 1)
    - 17 de julio (Black Journal), 1965; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 2)
    - Octubre (Florida - Black Journal), 1965; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 3)
    - Diciembre (Black Journal), 1965; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 4)
    - Febrero (Black Journal), 1966; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 5)
    - Lunes, 7 de marzo (Black Journal); Mayo (Black Journal); Viernes, 8 de noviembre (Black Journal); Febrero (Black Journal), 1966-1974; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 6)
    - Sábado, 16 de abril (Black Journal), 1966; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 7)
    - Junio (Black Journal); Diciembre (Black Journal), 1966-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 8)
    - Viernes, 19 de agosto (Black Journal); Noviembre (Black Journal), 1966-1978; 1 folder (Box B-001110, Folder 9)
    - Jueves, 6 de octubre (Black Journal); 25 de octubre (Black Journal); Enero (Black Journal), 1966-1973; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 1)
    - 29 de diciembre (Galeao - Black Journal); Octubre (Black Journal); Martes, 23 de abril (Black Journal), 1967-1968; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 2)
    - Diciembre 30 (Centinela Journal), 1966-1968; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 3)
    - Enero (Black Journal), 1967; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 4)
    - 27 de mayo (Black Journal), 1967; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 5)
    - Lunes, 12 de junio (Black Journal), 1967; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 6)
    - Lunes, 11 de septiembre (Black Journal), 1967-1968; 1 folder (Box B-001111, Folder 7)
    - Lunes, 10 de julio (Black Journal), 1968; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 1)
    - Sábado, 7 de septiembre (Black Journal), 1968-1970; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 2)
    - Noviembre (Black Journal), 1968-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 3)
    - Enero (Mar del Plaza - Black Journal), 1969; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 4)
    - Viernes, 21 de febrero (Black Journal), 1969; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 5)
    - Mayo (Black Journal), 1969; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 6)
    - Agosto (Black Journal); Septiembre (Black Journal), 1969-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 7)
    - Diciembre (Black Journal), 1969; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 8)
    - Miércoles, 25 de febrero (Black Journal), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001112, Folder 9)
      Contains insert from 1956; the body of the journal was written in 1970.
    - 22 de abril (Meridiano Spiral Journal), circa 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 1)
    - Julio (Black Journal), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 2)
    - Septiembre (Black Journal), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 3)
    - Sábado, 5 de diciembre (Black Journal), 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 4)
    - Diario en China - (Marca Éxito 100 hojas Notebook), 1971; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 5)
    - Junio (Black Journal), 1970-1971; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 6)
    - Lunes, 3 de enero (Black Journal), 1972; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 7)
    - Junio (Black Journal), 1970-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 8)
    - Septiembre (Black Journal), 1972; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 9)
    - Mayo (Black Journal), 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001113, Folder 10)
    - Lunes, 25 de junio (Black Journal), 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 1)
    - 27 de junio (Diario en China - Marca Éxito 100 hojas Notebook), 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 2)
    - Agosto 12 (Red Journal), 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 3)
    - Viernes, 15 de marco (Black Journal), 1974; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 4)
    - Julio (Black Journal), 1971-1974; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 5)
    - Abril (Black Journal), 1975; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 6)
    - Septiembre 10 (Black Journal), 1975; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 7)
    - Enero (Black Journal), 1976; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 8)
    - Noviembre 8 (Black Journal), 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 9)
    - Domingo, 3 de Abril (Black Journal), 1977; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 10)
    - Miércoles, 1 de Marco (Black Journal), 1978; 1 folder (Box B-001114, Folder 11)
    - Enero (Black Journal), 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box B-001115, Folder 1)
    - Julio 17 (Black Journal), 1980-1988; 1 folder (Box B-001115, Folder 2)
    - Lunes, 4 de Enero (Black Journal), 1982-1985; 1 folder (Box B-001115, Folder 3)
    - Mayo 21 (Black Journal), 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box B-001115, Folder 4)
    - Febrero (Black Journal), 2012-2014; 1 folder (Box B-001115, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Notebooks, 1953-2013; 10 boxes
    Chronologically with undated materials arranged first.
    Contains Piglia's research notebooks. Folder titles are derived from the following sources when available: cover titles, first entry date, and notebook brand in parenthesis.
    - (Avon 50 hojas Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 1)
    - Contra una literatura (Avon Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 2)
    - Cortázar (Blue Reporter Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 3)
    - Ideología I - (9 de julio Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 4)
    - Literatura norteamericana - (University Five Subject Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 5)
    - (Marca Éxito 40 hojas Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 6)
    - (No Cover Reporter Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 7)
    - (Norte 40 hojas Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 8)
    - Notas generales (Triunfo Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 9)
    - Realismo y literatura nacional (Avon Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001116, Folder 10)
    - (Scribe Block Taquigrafía 100 hojas Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 1)
    - Traducción - (Billiken 96 hojas Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 2)
    - Various Research Topics (Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001126, Folder 5)
    - Walter Benjamin: el artista como productor - (Gloria Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 3)
    - (Faded La Argentina Black Notebook), 1953-1960; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 4)
    - (Perlita Notebook), 1959; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 5)
    - Nuestro idioma - Cuaderno escolar; (La materia en el arte Pages of Notebook), 1960-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 6)
      Inset materials dated from 2013.
    - La Bolsa: Julián Martel (Blue Ripped Cover Notebook), circa 1961; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 7)
    - Cuaderno de Productores y Médicos de "Organización Sud-Este" (La materia en el Arte 98 hojas Notebook), 1961-1970; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 8)
    - Economía Europea en el XVI (La materia en el Arte 48 hojas Notebook), 1962; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 9)
    - Cuaderno de ideas y afines de mi hermano el otro (Espiral Notebook), 1963-1964; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 10)
    - Las Trampas (Avon Notebook), 1964; 1 folder (Box B-001117, Folder 11)
    - Loose pages, circa 1970s-1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 1)
    - Loose Pages - Travel to China, circa 1970s-1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001126, Folder 4)
    - Literatura argentina VII (Black Journal), circa 1970s-1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 2)
    - Teoría crítica, ideología, literatura VI (Black Notebook), circa 1970s-1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 3)
    - Notas sobre Marx - Grundrisse (Pink and purple Sarandi 90 hojas Notebook), 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre Proust (Blue Gloria 84 hojas Notebook), 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 5)
    - Respiración artificial (Monitor 47 hojas Notebook), 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 6)
    - Literatura ideología I (Black Notebook), circa 1972; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 7)
    - Notas de lectura (Red UCSD Notebook), 1972; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 8)
    - Hemingway (Librairie Papeterie Jseoph Gibert 180 pages Notebook), circa 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001118, Folder 9)
    - Notas de filosofía (No Cover Marca Registrada 50 hojas Notebook), circa 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 1)
    - Ideología y literatura - Notas de Lectura (Black Notebook), 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 2)
    - Borges (Yellow Spiral Notebook), circa 1974; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 3)
    - Borges (Blue Gloria 84 hojas Notebook), 1974; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 4)
    - Notas sobre ideología - Gramsci (Black Notebook), 1974; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 5)
    - Notas sobre ideología II - Foucault (Black Notebook), 1974-1975; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 6)
    - Respiración artificial (Black Notebook), 1974-1980; 1 folder (Box B-001119, Folder 7)
    - Historia argentina y crítica ideológica I (Black Notebook); Historia y literatura argentina III (Black Notebook), 1975-1979; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 1)
    - Notas sobre ideología II (Black Notebook), 1975-1982; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 2)
    - Notas sobre literatura y ideología - Borges (Black Notebook), 1975-1977; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 3)
    - Filosofía III - (Arte 29, 7 Notebook), circa 1976-1982; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 4)
    - Historia argentina (Blue Gloria 84 hojas Notebook), 1976; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 5)
    - Literatura argentina II: Historia (Black Notebook), 1976; 1 folder (Box B-001120, Folder 6)
    - Literatura Ideología II (Black Notebook), 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 1)
    - Notas sobre literatura e ideología - Borges (Black Notebook), 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 2)
    - (Mostly blank Black Notebook), circa 1977; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 3)
    - Novels (Yellow spiral-bound Joseph Gibert Librairie Papeterie Disques Notebook), 1977; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 4)
    - Teoría crítica - Literatura e ideología IV (Black Notebook), 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 5)
    - Zola (Loose pages), circa 1977; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 6)
    - Historia y literatura argentina IV (Black Notebook), 1978-1998; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 7)
      Notebook dated 1978. Inserts range from 1978-1998.
    - Teoría crítica - Notas de lectura literatura e ideología V (Black Notebook), circa 1978; 1 folder (Box B-001121, Folder 8)
    - Enrique Francisco de la Fuente (Green Éxito Oro 98 hojas Notebook), circa 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 1)
    - El libro del diario (Black Notebook), 1980-2012; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 2)
    - Ideología y literatura (Green Livewire Notebook), circa 1980-1981; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 3)
    - Literatura e historia argentina V (Black Notebook), circa 1980; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 4)
    - Teoría crítica - Literatura e ideología VI (Black Notebook), 1976-1987; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 5)
      Notebook from 1980. Contains inserts ranging from 1976-1987.
    - Bibliografía - University of California, San Diego (98 hojas Notebook), circa 1981-1984; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 6)
    - Notas sobre historia y argentina VI (Black Notebook), 1981-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 7)
    - Filosofía II (Avon Max 23 Notebook), circa 1982; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 8)
    - Filosofía IV (Arte 29, 7 Notebook), circa 1982; 1 folder (Box B-001122, Folder 9)
    - Notas sobre historia y literatura argentina VIII (Black Notebook), 1983-2012; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 1)
    - Historia y literatura argentina IX (Black Centinela Notebook), 1976-1985; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 2)
    - Filología (Printed Materials), 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 3)
    - Literatura argentina X (Black Notebook), 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 4)
    - (Black Notebook), circa 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 5)
    - Peter Szondi (Green Clairefontaine Notebook), circa 1990s-2000s; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 6)
    - La Muerte de Tolstoi (Pocket Memo 60 Sheets Notebook), 1999; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 7)
    - El Laboratorio del Escritor (Red Clairefontaine Notebook); Ideología (Red Clairefontaine Notebook), 2000-2009; 1 folder (Box B-001123, Folder 8)
    - Michel de Certeau (Pink Clairefontaine Notebook), 2001; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 1)
    - La Paraguaya (Black Moleskine Notebook), 2003-2011; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 2)
      Notebook dated 2006. Inserts date from 2003-2011.
    - Escritura codificada (Small black Moleskine Notebook), 2005-2011; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 3)
    - Filadelfia (Green Clairefontaine Notebook), 2005-2009; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 4)
    - Blanco Nocturno - Libro I (Red Clairefontaine Notebook), 2008-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 5)
    - Capítulo 18 - Archivo (Block A5 Reporter Notebook), circa 2009; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 6)
    - Historia conceptual (Black Brügge Notebook), 2011-2013; 1 folder (Box B-001124, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: Address Books and Agendas, 1970-2003; 2 boxes
    Contains Piglia's address books and agendas. Piglia also used his address books and agendas as occassional journal and research entries. Folder titles are derived from the following sources when available: cover titles, first entry date, and notebook brand in parenthesis.
    - Address Book (Balar No. 303 Refillable Address Book), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 1)
    - Address Book (No Cover Address Book), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 2)
    - Loose Pages (Black Agenda Notebook), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 3)
    - Agenda (Red Agenda Book), 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 4)
    - Agenda (Black Spiral Notebook), circa 1971-1974; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 5)
    - Agenda (Black Agenda Book), circa 1972-1985; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 6)
    - Agenda (Black Agenda Book), 1973; 1 folder (Box B-001125, Folder 7)
    - Agenda (Black Ready Office S.A. Agenda Book), circa 1976-1982; 1 folder (Box B-001126, Folder 1)
    - Agenda (Art No. 6 Agenda Witcel Book), 1984; 1 folder (Box B-001126, Folder 2)
    - Avon (Gray Agenda Book), 2003; 1 folder (Box B-001126, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Writings, 1962-2016; 14 boxes
  This series is organized by subseries, then alphabetically by folder title.
  Contains complete or nearly complete drafts and published versions of Piglia's articles, novels, short stories, and film scripts. Much of the material in the drafts section contains typewritten and computer print-out spiral bound drafts with handwritten annotations and corrections on loose paper. The series also contains files of various publishing contracts and legal documents.
  - Subseries 1: Drafts, 1962-2016; 12 boxes
    Alphabetically, by folder title.